

# Karina Macancela



### **Summary**

I am a creative software developer and contemporary artist living in NYC. For the past three years, I have focused on creating applications and managing projects for clients. I have always been a curious individual, interested in various subjects with a desire to positively contribute to the community. I am looking to work in an environment that challenges me, with an innovative team where I can continue growing and learning.



### **Experience**

04/2017 present

### Senior Associate

Infosys - New York, NY

- I have been working closely with clients on-site as a software consultant.
- I worked with well-known health insurance company, Aetna, for two years as a software developer and project manager. This allowed me to get experience in developing and managing projects from start to finish.
- I was trained extensively in both roles. Meanwhile, I continuously communicate and organize with our offshore team.

02/2018 -05/2019

### **Associate Project Manager**

Aetna - Hartford, CT (Infosys Client)

- Worked with project managers and stakeholders to track project scope, schedule, and cost.
- Assisted in preparing the project financials such as labor and non-labor budget reports, major milestones, and forecasting reports.
- Performed activities such as creating audit records, validating approvals, and conducting compliance audits.

06/2017 -02/2018

### **Associate Software Developer**

Aetna - Hartford, CT (Infosys Client)

- Developed, tested, and supported various APIs for different consumers based on their requirements using IBM API Connect.
- Utilized Splunk to check logs for errors in order to debug API failures.
- Worked closely with the DevOps team to create an automated and faster way to deploy APIs.
- Coordinated with offshore talent to gather requirements from consumers for API development.
- Utilized Git to upload completed APIs to the companies private repository so the DevOps team could automate its deployment into testing environments.

11/2016 -04/2017

### Full Stack Developer Trainee

Revature - Flushing, NY

- Used HTTP Servlet to handle GET and POST requests.
- Created a Business Delegate to build a bridge between business logic and backend.
- Incorporated POJO Java beans to work with a SQL relational database.
- Used JDBC to allow clients to access the database.



#### E-mail

karymacancela@gmail.com

#### Website

https://kmacancela.github.io

#### **GitHub**

https://github.com/kmacancela

#### LinkedIn

https://linkedin.com/in/kmacancela



## Languages

Java

**HTML** 

CSS

JavaScript

SQL

Swift



### **Skills**

Spring

Hibernate

Microservices

Object Relational Mapping

**Bootstrap** 

**Project Management** 

Agile Methodology

DevOps



### **Software**

Eclipse

IntelliJ IDEA

Xcode

Oracle Database

MySQL

Git

Jenkins

Adobe Photoshop

Sony Vegas Pro

- Used ORM framework in order to map beans to tables in our relational database in SQL Developer.
- Implemented Continuous Integration with project collaborators using Slack and Git.



## **Education**

08/2011 -06/2016

### **Queens College**

City University of New York - Flushing, NY

- Bachelor's in Computer Science with 3.1 GPA
  - Worked with IBM Watson as a team where we brainstormed a scenario that could vastly benefit from Watson and presented it to a IBM conference in the city.
- Bachelor's in Applied Mathematics with 3.4 GPA
  - Wrote a 40-page book called "Mathematics in the Real World," aimed at helping educators in how to teach mathematics to high school students in order for our kids to appreciate the benefits of mathematics around us.



## References



References Available Upon Request